VINCENT CANNALLA

Phone: (949) 682 6155 | Email: vcannall@ucsd.edu

Professional Summary

Accomplished and personable computer science and engineering student with a solid history of achievement in computer science. Motivated leader with strong organizational and prioritization abilities. Areas of expertise include programming, software development, and teaching.

Skills

Data Structures and Science:

Excellent understanding of data structures and organization of data Relevant Courses: CSE 12, 100

Programming:

Fluent: Java, C, C++

Proficient: Python, HTML, Ruby on Rails, Javascript, PostgreSQL Relevant Courses: CSE 8a-b, 30

Software Development:

Technologies: Java, Android, Google

Play Services

Tools: Android Studio, JUnit, Jira, Git,

Android ADT

Techniques: Agile Software Process, Design Patterns, Mobile software

development

Relevant Courses: CSE 110

Leadership:

Lead tutor, previous head of tutoring program at ETHS.

Teaching:

Years of experience as a math tutor and computer science teacher.

Education

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE - UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA SAN DIEGO

Dean's List Honoree, 6 semesters, 3.4 GPA

Work Experience

Curriculum and Instructional Software Developer, Jan 2017 - Jan 2018 UCSD DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATIONAL STUDIES

- Created both backend and frontend architecture to enhance the Bootstrap learning platform to accommodate more interactive learning and professional development experience for students and teacher.
- Contributed to improving and developing new curriculum for the UCSD tested APCS Principles curriculum and teacher professional development course for high schoolers.
- Created, checked, and improved the curriculum on three learning management systems: Bootstap, Canvas, and Moodle.
- Worked with a team of undergrads to find ways to improve the curriculum for both students and teachers in local high schools, with the expectation that our work could be offered nationwide.

Computer Science Instructor

JUNIOR ACADEMY- SALLY RIDE SCIENCE CAMP JUNE 2017 - JULY 2017

- Instructed courses to teach coding through game design using unity to instill a interest for computer science in young students
- Supervised groups of up to 20 during week long instruction periods

RISE UP 4 CS, GEORGIA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY JAN 2017 - MAY 2017

- Facilitated in-person and remote tutoring sessions which allowed students to better understand computer science
- Engaged computing experiences for underrepresented students in computing who are in Advanced Placement (AP) Computer Science courses.

APCS Principles Course Intern, Sep 2016 - Dec 2016 UCSD DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATIONAL STUDIES

- Developed new curriculum for the teacher professional development course for high schoolers.
- Worked in a team of undergrads to find ways to improve the curriculum for both students and teacher in local (San Diego) high schools